..Chandler 
195 Marlborough St. 
Boston

10-4-1912

(typewritten) Dearest Mother.

Just at this moment I am longing for my man. Why should he ever leave me
now that I am his and he is mine? Can you give me any comfort? Of course
you never could have had that tremulous feeling about him,
(insert)father, that I have about Herbert. We are so different. We do
love each other so much. Do you believe there was ever quite so nice a man as he? Do tell
me just what you really think and try not to be prejudiced thats a dear mother. 
(end typewritten)
(begin handwritten) Pa wrote this on the machine just for a start and tells me to 
go on with it. Two letters have come from you one this morning & one just now. Aren’t you
having a good time out there or isn’t there any thing else for you to do? 
(2)
As for us the presents have been pouring in. A check for $50 from Aunt Ida. Glass & 
silver pitcher from Eliot Hubbard & wife. Lovely green enamelled & silver chain from the
Uphams. Square (insert) glass(end insert) plat from the Barfours. Arts & crafts sugar 
tray from the Harry Scotts. Pair of Tiffany ho.... candle sticks from Peters & Ward. 
Trials (?) lace jacket from Aunt Kate. Really very handsome lace too. I can’t think of
any more but there are 4 more waiting to be opened when Herbert comes in about half an
hour. It’s getting pretty boring writing so many of the same kind of letter but I 
suppose I’ll get more the hang of it. Pa has just tried some more powdered agar agar
having eaten a great quantity of supper he just had to push it down with a spoon. Got
a telegram from Patty from Albany “Daisy Austin with alcohol”. At least that is what I
got over the wire later. Any suit(?) round the telegram which said ‘Bathe it often’. Most
of the stuff as I said is on the pill box. My feller is 

(p2 landscape lhs) The china closet door is still flying the chimney sweep hasn’t come. 
All the spiders haven’t gone & there is less(?) rest for us. 

(p1 landscape, lhs) furious! About the lunch basket Ethel has been looking into the 
matter & I think it would be fine to give it to me & then we can get just what suits.
I should suggest centerpiece & doilys are particularly good kind of thing to have. I 
didn’t believe she really wasn’t that [...] when she said it. I was one those? polite
kind & [...] great in the country now wish [I?] was there. Had my picture taken props 
coming tomorrow. I guess we look more of a fool than ever. ..bia not due till Saturday 
night or Sunday moring. Ethel goes to Framingham just the same. But she is all of a 
twist. Anybody can see it.  Don’t hurry home though you won’t gain any thing by it &
its [...] [...] [...]
love from us three your Helen