1913-11-1-helwin-mother-1 and 1913-11-1-helwin-mother-3 (right)

(letterhead) Mena House Hotel,
Pyramids, Cairo

November 1st 1913

My dear Parents,

Almost a week has passed out here and nothing of moment has happened except the arrival 
of the Bates family. I have all Oric’s seeming familiarity with the Arabic language in 
the way he throws out words in his gay way, there is nothing to it. Herbert speaks a 
thousand times better. Natica is getting the habit too.  Well I don’t know but what()t’s 
a pretty good one & at (?) here because you get used to using words that way. Natica has
also learned to write the alphabet. Still she has got three arabic grammars & I’ve only
got the first volume of one. they really make a very good couple though Oric and “Tica
dear” only I don’t think they are having half such a good time
 
1913-11-1-helwin-mother-2 (right)
 
loving as we do. We trail round together so, while Oric goes into town for the day and
she stays out here. But perhaps they are saving on the meal tickets.
 
I’ve been up to the Reisners to spend the morning twice now while Herbert dr.. on some
of his things that didn’t get finished last summer. Thus I have seen some of that crowd 
up there. Natica is still full of her wedding but sees .... in camp life 
heretofore unthought of. She is amusing about the way she talks of always having done
thus and so when they have only been out here about three days. We recognized them
coming, at least Herbert did by Oric’s jockey seat on his donkey. They haven’t the 
slightest idea what they are going to do next or whether they are even going to Siwa at 
all.

1913-11-1-helwin-mother-2 (left)

They hope to get to Algiers by the middle of January so you may see them there on your 
way or not. Any way apply at the consuls for information. Oric always goes to the consul
on arriving at a place. The Reisners are all very pleasant. Little Mary has a young
gazelle which has to be fed from a goat, also a small monkey, two donkeys and any 
amount of kittens. There is a poor kind of miserable looking dog that hangs around too.
Their house is nothing compared to ours quite low ceilings I don’t think the floor is 
paved just mats down to keep your shoes from getting full of dirt. There was quite a
sharp shower one day I was up there which leaked through everywhere.

1913-11-1-helwin-mother-3 (left)

Still they spent the summer out there very happily. The great excitement is the army that
has a camp behind the hotel. They are forever having battles and running miles over the
desert. In fact there’s really not a dull moment out here though there are only about ten
other people staying in the hotel. Tourists aren’t very thick yet, a few camel loads of 
them go up to the sphinx daily but the real rush has hardly begun. I am glad we aren’t 
still in Cairo. Matter of fact I think we would burst if we were. Lysol is used 
copiously by Miss Fisher and me, but its for sand flies mostly. I have only seen one 
little bit of a flea who I don’t think did any damage. These sand flies are particularly
vicious. They are like little green midges and they just chew and chew

1913-11-1-helwin-mother-4 

(letterhead) Mena House Hotel,
Pyramids, Cairo

There is no net small enough to keep them off at night and then they will get under the 
bed clothes too. It seems Lysol is the favorite English disinfectant so she was
perfectly used to using it, although hadn’t realized it’s efficacy in the bite line. 
Nothing touches Herbert, he says he has been strong immune? I tell him he is tough and
sour so we get on very well. Fisher has done yards of crochet and I have idled away
quantities of time, sleeping mostly. I tried a little sketching this morning with no 
success whatsoever. I must do a little more and try different methods to see if I can’t
really do something.

1913-11-1-helwin-mother-5

Before I forget it, we were talking about those little envelopes I left behind for
announcements. Herbert doesn’t want one sent to Helen Munroe as he is going to cable her,
so if you will pick that one out and destroy it, it might be as well. Also I can’t
remember whether I had Charlotten Allen down but I think she would be interested. We
can’t make up our minds what to call it if it’s a girl so expect anything. Anyway the
doctor promised it wasn’t twins. Tell Ethel that I’ve finally got the silver box and Pa 
that his birthday present has also inadvertently arrived. We will keep it till you come.
As for our Voltunas? pictures they haven’t turne dup yet and I for one don’t ever 
expect to see them. Thoughts turn to bed so good night lots of love from us both ever
your Helen


