(1)
On board S.S. "Cedric"
October 31 1912

Dearest family,
Here we are off at last. Battery 
Park is disappearing over the stern sheets
and there is nothing ahead of us but 
Coney Island and a clear sea.
Mother letter and Ethels and Daland
telegram recieved with lots of appreciation.
After I sent that letter yesterday, we
sallied forth [] and [turned] a good 
[trick] at Tiffany, getting a []
lamp which we told them to 
pack with care and thought that
unless you are aching to see it
now you might leave it as it is and 
take it North [] next summer.
(2)
Now I got on pairs of [] for 
the London fog which I hear are
very damp also an egg to darn
stockings over and chintz to cover
the pllows which I'm going
to begin on almost immediatley.
Before I forget it what is the []
doctor's name in London that
Daland went to. We saw O! O!
Delphine last night. Robert W. [hardwright]
and others. Very amusing. None of 
them came to see us off progably
thought it would be [deleted] tactless.
[] and E. [Hatford] we saw
in Belmont. We [deleted] certainly
are "de Luxe" here our [] stateroom
(3)
and a bath that is huge. [Beats] the public one by a long sight
There are only about 60 passangers on board and 
anything but the exotic type of whom we know none. I
picked up one old lady by picking up her handkercheif.
We are still very pleased with ourselves and havn't
had our first quarrel yet. I doubt now whether we 
do at all. Enclosed please find a little token for
father. He can substitute it for Agar-Agar or kindling just
as he likes. It seems to be done to [parks] flowers with
it. We are going to have a Halloween party tonight. 
We havn't decided [quite] how to celebrate. But we are going
(4)
to use autumn foliage for the decorations
We are going to have a chaste and simple little
Halloween party tonight and we will drink all of
your healths one by one and toddle off to bed 
to start in getting good and rested for our
gay times with the crowned heads of Europe.
We are working up gradually with our de looks
cabin suite - you all just ought to see it.
Tables and chairs, mechanical pianos, palms,
cut glass chandeliers all in unostentatious profusion.
We are like two children with alot of new
toys. Love to all of you and goodby. Its lunch time.
Ever yours,
Helen
Love to Mother, Father, Sister, Brother
We were all ready to start at 9:30 AM and the
boat didn't go till 12. We have [lost] nothing so far.