1913-12-7

5490

(headed notepaper) Mena House Hotel, Pyramids Cairo

December 7th 1913

Dearest Mother

Here it is two days after the fatal moment and nothing has happened yet
except that yesterday I discovered a filling had dropped out of one of
my teeth so we (popped?) in town and had the hole stopped up quick while
there was yet time.  It only took about twenty minutes so as along as we
were away from (...?) we thought we would go on a spree. This idea of
spreeing didn’t occur till we had got on the car, so off we got again at
the Zoo and had a time looking at the animals and eating chocolate. Next
year they say

5491 and 5492 (right)

Kitchener wants the lions round loose the way they were in Rome (wasn’t
it?) with just a ditch between the frightened spectator and the roaring
monarch of the desert. However the general gossip is that Lord Hardi191nge
is going to resign from India and Kitchener will take his place there,
with lots more chances at booty. Did I ever tell you the story of the
marble lions and K? He was asked to a grand dinner or lunch or something
on the opening of the Gezireh Casino which was rearranged from one of
Ismail’s old palace buildings. In front of it were four marble lions.
When K went in to the post his eye lit upon the lions, he said to his
Aide, “Those lions would look well on my front lawn in England”.  Along
towards the end of the repast the manager of  Casino came along and
wanted to take a flash light of the party and asked K if he minded.
“Yes”, said K.

5491 and 5492 (left) “I hate the damned things & I won’t have it”. The
manager went off in a depression of spirits. The aide said to himself
“Ha. here is my chance to practice diplomacy and make everybody happy”.
So calling the manager to him, he told him of K’s delight in the lions
suggesting an offer of one of them, with the idea that maybe K would
then allow him to (deleted word) take the picture. So by and bye back
went the manager to this noble lord, rubbing his hands in the correct
approved fashion, and said that he had heard that his excellency had
taken a fancy to the lions, if so it would delight the manager if he
would take one of them. “Oh yes” says K “They are fine and it would be a
pity to break the set, I’ll take the lot!” The poor old manager kind of
gasped, but still having his picture in mind, he asked again

5490 (left) if he might take it “Go ahead” said K. Now whether a
flashlight is worth four marble lions or even two is a question. Any way
to complete the story, he caused the manager to have them removed to an
army train that was leaving about that time, and made the home going
regiment carry them along on their transport free. Having written all
this out I’m sure I told you last year about it but never mind. Again
they do say as how K goes on hunting trips in the Soudan and never pays
a penny, just leaves when he gets through and all the poor young
subalterns have to pay all the expenses from their meager store.  Still
everybody speaks well of him as a rule, though he has his foibles.
Yesterday morning the Mahemat (?)came back from Mecca. Herbert didn’t
dare let me go and I was a little nervous at the idea myself, in case we
got caught in the crowd, but we sent Miss Fisher

5493 (right) (letterhead) Mena House Hotel Pyramids, Cairo

who had a beautiful time. The hotel bus went in to the citadel where the
procession was going to be, and they all sat on top of it and watched
things, the Baroness went along too so she had a friend. Lots of
soldiers and four richly comparisoned camels seemed to be the
processions there were no pilgrims, but I wish we had gone, still maybe
next year we can see it. Herbert saw a funny thing the other day. A
great procession of people dressed in yellow, walking and singing,
beautiful camels all fixed up with rugs and things. Lots of pipers
playing

5494 (right) Yankee Doodle of all tunes. A man playing a piano on a
cart. he asked what was happening and was told it was pilgrims returning
from Mecca. He wanted to know if they were the pilgrims in yellow. “Oh
no” said the man “the pilgrims are riding horses”. Herbert looked again
searching for the horses and saw a man and a very small boy riding two
miserable little creatures... & they were the only ones.

The greatest wonder happened the other day, our films came back of the
(??volcano). I told you that, but with them came a letter saying that
they were sorry there had been so much delay and by the next mail they
would send a cheque for those they had used. We got some that

5494 (left) weren’t ours and some we remembered taking right up close
didn’t come at all, so we thought the mention of the cheque was as a
stopper to our mouths, and we would never hear any thing more from the
Mirror. BUT two days ago we got a cheque for 4 guineas. Now what do you
know about that! We showed it to all our friends in the hotel. It’s on a
great big piece of paper suitable for framing. Herbert’s in town now
looking up a reliable framers. No really he is seeing Maspero before he
starts up the river for his grand annual tour of inspection.

Natica is still in bed and has had a bad time lately so I haven’t
(deleted) seen her, but Oric really is off for Masr Matube (??)

5493 (left) next Thursday I think. An interesting note on the Bates
family, they send their washing in town (deleted) by their Arab who
finds a laundry, has it washed, and brings it out again wrapped in pink
paper. This amused us a good deal because we’ve been taking ours in in a
bag, in fear and trembling thinking it was not done but considering that
we can get four weeks work done there for one here, we thought we had
better. It’s just as good too. At least I can’t see any difference. But
you would think 2 millions would cover the work expensive laundry bill.
What’s the use in having it if it doesn’t save trouble. Another item of
interest was that a honeymoon couple arrived hired the first horses in
the stable for a week, went out the first day, and broke the

5496 (letterhead) Mena House Hotel Pyramids, Cairo

ankle fo the very best one, so that he had to be shot forthwith.
Everybody thought she was the Sackville-West girl but it transpires that
she was Sackville without the West and really much sweller and no
scandal. They danced the tango last night together very prettily. By the
way Herbert wants to know, it was at my suggestion, if you have kept the
Boston Museums Bulletins, if so would you mind getting them together
(insert above line= no matter how ancient) for him as he is keen on
having any writing Reisner may have done. Don’t send them but just stack
them some where

5495

so that next spring he could get them. Also he said that as Eddy is
going to marry my younger sister, he must be his younger brother anyway
regardless, and as Herbert is only thirty Eddy can’t be too old for
Ethel. I just put this in for an idea.

The pictures I’m sending along because we have selected the best & glued
them in the book and these are the refuse.

Don’t worry over my falling off in my attire. My under clothes are all
rotting, but my outer appearance is very swell, pearl earrings and
ruffles to say nothing of new white on my hat.

Lots of love from us both. I suppose you’ll be in the midst of Christmas
when this gets to you. hope you won’t be exhausted. Ever yours Have
finished Corpaton(?abook?) after lunch concentrated effort.
