Wednesday Jan. 8th 1913
Dear mother,
Last night we came over for good. Bag and baggage from the 
hotel. We rode our two good trusty steeds, and the great camels, 
all except the dog who rode on his four little footsies. The stud 
fare building were moved from the banks of the Nile. Being a teat.
And the caravan started . It was black night by the time it arrived 
So I couldn’t take a picture. It would have been one all right
too. Daland’s letter just arrived before we left the hotel. Last
Saturday I tried a first ride over here. had lunch and 
then back. Sunday I was so stiff that it was impossible to move
however I managed a post card or two which you may have
already received. Daland’s little token hasn’t has yet arrived doubtless
it will turn up. This place is full of novelty. For instance 
there are no locks or handle on any doors and they have to
be kept shut by a block of stone which is never quite heavy 
enough to keep out all the drought. So the wind whistles
dismally all night and the day withers upon the fellows. None
of the furniture is here except a few chairs and the bed which
came from England but the Jones found a servile cook somewhere
who takes to vinegar flavoring & cochineal coloring in the frosting on
the cake. Hence our stuff is in the greatest mess it’s yet been in
and there seems to be no hope. There isn’t any use unpacking anything
as there is nowhere to put it. But when things are ready I think 
we will be pretty well fixed. The house is very attractive I will 
have by far the nicest room although there is no sun in there whatsoever 
but the few here. Only the dining room and kitchen, it’s something 
to be avoided apparently. Mrs. [Bying] came out to lunch today 
too amusing, she wears a wig I think, and is very slightly able
I don’t know if she does any less than you did in your day. 
We brought quantities of native baskets for scrap affairs and then some
Marvelous embroidery for sofa cushions all on the house. That they have been
very funny about the furnishings like curtains etc. instead of getting 
native stuff that goes with the house which [is] the best they have had stuff
Sent from England that is the worst looking stuff any way. So far
our end we thought we might save up a few pennies and get some
Curtains on our own account. So there is the stay in a nutshell.
I wish you could see the place. When everything is settled I’ll take a lot 
of pictures inside and out and send them along. Today is Cook day
and all the tourists are steaming over the hill opposite to the rest house.
The boy is waiting to take the letters so I’ve got to stop. Good bye with 
lots of love Helen. Herbert and I get along very well together so there is no need to 
worry...
