<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Letter dated 12-06-1912 addressed to Mrs Chandler</title>
                <author>
                    <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Herbert Winlock</persName>
                </author>
                <editor>
                    <persName ref="#SLK">Dr. Sarah L. Ketchley</persName>
                </editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>EBA Interns</resp>
                    <persName ref="#RR">Rachel Rodney</persName>
                    <persName ref="#SM">Sesha Manchirau</persName>
                    <persName ref="#CR">Connor Rafferty</persName>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>The Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Washington, Seattle WA 98195 U.S.A.</addrLine>
                </address>
                <availability>
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This work is
                        licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0
                        International License."></licence>
                </availability>
                <date when="2018"> 2011-2018 </date>
                <distributor>The Emma B. Andrews Diary Project</distributor>
            </publicationStmt>
            <notesStmt>
                <note>1912-08-17</note>
            </notesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Helen Winlock Archive</title>
                    <author>
                        <persName ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen Winlock</persName>
                    </author>
                    <orgName ref="#APS">Massachussets Historical Society</orgName>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Boston,Massachussetts</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>
                    <persName ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma B. Andrews</persName> is best remembered
                    for her association with the millionaire lawyer turned archaeologist/art and
                    antiquities collector, <persName ref="#Davis_Theodore">Theodore M.
                        Davis</persName>. Traveling to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>
                    with him between 1889 and 1912, she kept detailed journals of these voyages
                    along the <placeName ref="#Nile_River">Nile</placeName>, including his important
                    yet under-reported excavations of 20 significant tombs in the <placeName
                        ref="#Valley_of_the_Kings">Valley of the Kings</placeName>. <persName
                            ref="#Andrews_Emma_B">Emma</persName> provides a vital commentary on the
                    archaeology and pioneering Egyptologists of the time. She paints a revealing
                    picture of the lives of the colonial gentry and the cultural and scientific
                    literati in <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName> at the dawn of the
                    twentieth century. To date, her diaries are unpublished; analysis of the
                    contents of 19 volumes will afford scholars and a general audience information
                    about an important historical resource for the first time. Since its inception
                    in 2010, the scope of our project has broadened to include the transcription and
                    digitization of a wide range of primary historical material from the 'Golden
                    Age' of Egyptian archaeology detailed in the Research section of this website.
                    The Emma B. Andrews Diary Project is one of the founding partners of Newbook
                    Digital Texts. We are proud to offer undergraduate and graduate Digital
                    Humanities education and internships.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <listPerson>
                    <person role="editor" sex="F">
                        <persName ref="#SLK">Dr. Sarah L. Ketchley</persName>
                        <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
                        <occupation>Affiliate Instructor</occupation>
                        <listEvent>
                            <event>
                                <p>Project Director 2010-present</p>
                            </event>
                        </listEvent>
                    </person>
                    <!-- Repeat as necessary adding new team member -->
                    
                </listPerson>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2018-03-15" who="#SLK">
                <p>#SLK updated TEI Header.</p>
                <!-- Repeat as necessary, most recent at the top -->
            </change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>We have roared at <persName ref="#Winlock_Ethel">Ethel</persName>s letters but we
                deprecate the two children's tendencies towards unrestraint and turkey trotting
                since <persName ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName>'s steadying influence has
                gone</p>
            <p><address rend="embossed">
                    <addrLine>Telephone 4949 Mayfair</addrLine>
                </address></p>
            <p><address rend="embossed">
                    <addrLine>52, Jermyn Street, S.W.</addrLine>
                </address></p>
            <p><date when="1912-06-12">XII 6 1912</date></p>
            <p>We don't approve of turkey trotting but then maybe we are of a past generation - old
                fogy married folks.</p>
            <p>Dear<persName ref="#Chandler_Mrs"> Mrs. Chandler</persName></p>
            <p>Well here we are in <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName> still on our
                honeymoon. It's quite a story and I will have to go way back and take it up where
                    <persName ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> left off at <placeName
                    ref="#Highclere">Highclere</placeName>. She's been trying to make me write for a
                week now and and I've been putting it off for her to write and so several chapters
                of our novel have come out without you getting the installments. First for the
                illustrations. There are three of <persName ref="#Ermintrude_Lady">Lady
                    Erminitrude</persName> and two of <persName ref="#Algy_Lord">Lord
                    Algy</persName> at their cozy little shooting box down in <placeName
                    ref="#Berkshire">Berks</placeName>. (In two the shooting box creeps into the
                back ground). <persName ref="#Carnarvon_Lord">Lord Carnarvon</persName> took</p>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <p>one of <persName ref="#Ermintrude_Lady">Lady Erminitrude</persName> and <persName
                    ref="#Algy_Lord">Lord Algy</persName> together and had it enlarged so big - two
                feet by three - that it won't get into this envelope. He sent <persName
                    ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> a great big print yesterday with his name
                down in the corner just like a professional photographer. When the Lords are
                abolished he will be a success at his trade.</p>
            <p>Well we left <placeName ref="#Highclere">Highclere</placeName> on a Monday morning
                with <persName ref="#Johnny_Dr">Dr. Johnny</persName> - a name that sounds as
                peculiarly flippant as the man who is tagged with it. But its only a disguise for
                one of the best of the younger London surgeons. I believe <persName
                    ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> has mentioned him before. We got back here
                to the rooms and had a joyful time unpacking. <persName ref="#Dexter_Mary">Mary
                    Dexter</persName> had given us a rather footless lecture on the superiority of
                English servants and we had a fine sample of it. The ploughboy and milk maid who
                packed our bags had packed a great boot of mine in one of <persName
                    ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName>'s silk slipper covers and jammed her
                patent leather slippers loose among my shoes, and then with that for a starter they
                had shown a diabolic ingenuity in keeping up their original</p>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <p>ideas of packing. We saw <persName ref="#Dexter_Mary">Mary Dexter</persName> next day
                and told her.</p>
            <p>During the next two days we kept up our [rounds] of showing off <persName
                    ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName>'s swell dresses at the swellest places. We
                had lunch with <persName ref="#Harcourt_Smith_Sir_Cecil">Sir Cecil</persName> and
                    <persName ref="#Harcourt_Smith_Lady">Lady Harcourt-Smith</persName> in
                    <placeName ref="#South_Kensington">South Kensington</placeName> and had tea at
                the <orgName ref="#Lyceum_Club">Lyceum Club</orgName> with a great aunt of my
                Sister <persName ref="#Helen_Sister">Helen</persName>'s. We bought saddles, our
                boots were finished, <persName ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> tried on her
                riding habits, our wicker straw chairs and <persName ref="#Chandler_Ethel"
                    >Ethel</persName>s lunch basket with the gold rimmed plates came from the Army +
                Navy stores and finally we packed four heavy trunks with useless stuff and sent them
                by long sea around to <placeName ref="#Marseilles">Marseilles</placeName>.</p>
            <p><persName ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> meanwhile had been feeling a bit out
                of sorts. We laid it down at first to our last spree - dinner at the Berkley, the
                theatre and supper at the <name type="hotel" ref="#Savoy">Savoy</name> but by
                Thanksgiving day she was sort of miserable. I sent for <persName ref="#Johnny_Dr"
                    >Dr. Johnny</persName> next day because I know him well. To cut it short she
                probably got a chill at <placeName ref="#Highclere">Highclere</placeName> which
                developped into <hi rend="underline">coli cystitis</hi>. That it seems is the way
                doctors express having little worms with wriggly bodies and yellow eyes and gaping
                mouths</p>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <p>that chew your bladder. <persName ref="#Johnny_Dr">Dr. Johnny</persName> has seen her
                daily. We vetoed the idea of a trained nurse or a nursing home and he has taken us
                under his charge and seen that everything is all right. The worst of its all over
                and she's on the mend now so don't worry. We are taking every precaution and
                    <persName ref="#Johnny_Dr">Dr. J</persName> is a notoriously cautious person and
                I really don't think she can help bring well in a week. Meantime we have put off
                sailing another two weeks. Fortunately I ran across a chance of purchasing a
                collection of manuscripts for <persName ref="#Morgan_J_P">J.P.M.</persName> which
                involves about <measure type="currency">$40,000</measure> and that I have had orders
                from <placeName ref="#New_York">New York</placeName> to stay here for so <persName
                    ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName>'s little flurry has nothing to do with our
                being late to <placeName ref="#Egypt">Egypt</placeName>.</p>
            <p>Now this you needn't read to the family. She's been a perfect dear, this wife of
                mine. An illness like this on a honeymoon might be supposed to cast a gloom over
                things but she is such a darling its just brought us closer together and we've had a
                regular picnic out of it. She has been wonderfully good a patient just <persName
                    ref="#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> in fact - and I think she is happy - I am
                sure she is. With love <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Herbert</persName>.</p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
